mrowl.com 2019-03-31

# MrOwl Privacy Policy

### MrOwl Privacy Policy

MrOwl, Inc. (“MrOwl,” “we,” “our,” or “us”) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how your personal information is collected, used, and disclosed by MrOwl. This Privacy Policy applies to our website and our mobile apps for iPhone or Android mobile devices (collectively, our “Service”). By accessing or using our Service, you signify that you have read, understood, and agree to our collection, storage, use, and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service. 

**Please remember that information that you post in your MrOwl profile, to public branches, in comments on public branches, hearts, grabs, and follows are _publicly searchable, viewable and downloadable_. To review your choices, please see “Control Over Your Information” below.**

**
  1. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND FOR WHAT PURPOSE?
**

The categories of information we collect can include: 

    * **Information you provide to us directly.** We may collect personal information, such as your name or pseudonym, phone number, username, password, email address, address, and payment information when you register for our Service, sign up for our mailing list, make a purchase, or otherwise communicate with us. We may also collect any communications between you and MrOwl and any other information you provide to MrOwl. 

To protect your privacy, you may use MrOwl under a pseudonym if you prefer not to use your name or identity.

    * **Data collected through your use of the Service** We collect information about how you use the Service, your actions on the Service, and content you post to the Service, including the groups you belong to; your interaction with others on the Service; documents, photos and videos you post to the Service; and any other content you provide to the Service through messages, chat, or other functionalities (“User Content”). To share photos and video, we will access your device camera roll and camera with your permission. If you need to update your permissions, you can do so in the “Settings” app of your device. Please remember that MrOwl may, but has no obligation to, monitor, record, and store User Content to protect your safety or the safety of other users, to assist with regulatory or law enforcement efforts, or to protect and defend our rights and property. By using the Service, you consent to the recording, storage, and disclosure of such communications you send or receive for these purposes. 
    * **Information we receive from third-party sites you connect to our Service.** We may receive personal information about you from third parties and combine that with information we collect through our Service. For example, we may obtain information when you log in through a third-party social network or authentication service, such as Facebook or Google. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us, which could include your name, email address, address book and contacts, or other information. If you permit the third-party social network to share your friends list or address book with us, we may use this information to let you know what your friends are doing on our Service and to let your friends know what you are doing on the Service. We use this data to provide, enhance, and personalize the Service (e.g., to help connect you with or suggest friends within our Services). If you do not want to provide us with this data, you need to adjust the privacy settings on your social media account. The data we receive from these third-party sites is dependent upon that third party’s policies and your privacy settings on that third-party site. You should always review and, if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to our website or Service. 
    * **Address Book Information.** With your permission, MrOwl may access your contact list available on your mobile device, social media accounts, and email accounts so that you can locate your friends and contacts on the Service and invite your friends and contacts to connect with our Service. After sending these invitations, we may also send reminder emails to your invitees on your behalf, which may also include your name and photo. We will not use the information contained in your Address Book for any purpose other than to send invitations to your contacts at your request. 

We use this information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service, as well as to personalize and curate the Service, communicate directly with you, such as to send you email messages and push notifications, and permit you to communicate on the Service or invite others to join the Service. We may also send you Service-related emails or messages (e.g., account verification, updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices). For more information about your communication preferences, see “Control Over Your Information” below.

**
  2. HOW WE USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGY TO COLLECT INFORMATION
**

When you use our Service, visit our branches, read our emails, or otherwise engage with us through a computer or mobile device, we and our third-party partners, automatically collect information about how you access and use the Service and information about the device you use to access the Service.

We use this information to enhance and personalize your user experience, to monitor and improve our websites and services, and for other internal purposes. We typically collect this information through a variety of tracking technologies, including cookies, web beacons, embedded scripts, location-identifying technologies, and similar technology (collectively, “tracking technologies”). Information we collect automatically about you may be combined with other personal information we collect directly.

We and our third-party partners use tracking technologies to automatically collect usage and device information, such as:

    * **Information about how you access the Service,** for example, the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave our website, how frequently you access the Service, when and whether you open emails or click the links contained in emails, whether you access the Service from multiple devices, and other actions you take on the Service.
    * **Information about how you use the Service,** for example, the pages you visit, the links you click, the ads you view and click on, purchase information and your checkout process, your location when you access or interact with our Service, and other similar actions.
    * **Information about the computer, tablet, smartphone or other device you use,** such as your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, platform type, device type/model/manufacturer, operating system, date and time stamp, a unique ID that allows us to uniquely identify your browser, mobile device or your account (including, for example, a persistent device identifier or an Ad ID), and other such information.
    * **Analytics information.** We may collect analytics data, or use third-party analytics tools, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Service and to understand more about the demographics and behaviors of our users.

We, or the third party partners we use, may use the data collected through tracking technologies to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information, including targeted content and advertising; (c) identify and contact you across multiple devices; (d) provide and monitor the effectiveness of our Service; (e) perform analytics and detect usage patterns on our Service; (f) diagnose or fix technology problems; (g) detect or prevent fraud or other harmful activities, and (h) otherwise to plan for and enhance our service.

If you would prefer not to accept cookies, most browsers will allow you to: (i) change your browser settings to notify you when you receive a cookie, which lets you choose whether or not to accept it; (ii) disable existing cookies; or (iii) set your browser to automatically reject cookies. Please note that doing so may negatively impact your experience using the Service, as some features and services on our Service may not work properly. Depending on your mobile device and operating system, you may not be able to delete or block all cookies. You may also set your email options to prevent the automatic downloading of images that may contain technologies that would allow us to know whether you have accessed our email and performed certain functions with it.

We and our third-party partners may also use cookies and tracking technologies for advertising purposes. For more information about tracking technologies, please see “Third Party Tracking and Online Advertising” below.

**Do Not Track.** Although we do our best to honor the privacy preferences of our visitors, we are not able to respond to Do Not Track signals from your browser at this time.

**
  3. SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION
**

We may share your personal information in the instances described below. For further information on your choices regarding your information, see the “Control Over Your Information” section below.

Remember, our Service allows you to post content publicly and connect with others. **Your profile information, including your username, photo, and other bio information that you create, as well as the User Content that you post to the Service will be available publicly to other members of the Service by _default_ when you create a profile, interact with others on the Service in public groups, and post content to public spaces.**

We may share your personal information with: 

    * The public and other members of the Service. Your profile information and User Content you post to public areas of the Service, including public groups, will be viewable by others on the Service and the public. Please do not provide personal information you would not want to be public. You may be able to control the visibility of some of your information and actions in your Settings (see “Control Over Your Information” below); 
    * Other users of the Service. We share your information, such as your profile information and any User Content you post publicly, with third parties with whom you communicate on the Service. You control who you want to communicate with and what information you share; 
    * Third parties at your request. For example, you may have the option to share your activities on the Service with your friends through email, text, or on various social media networks; 
    * Other companies and brands owned or controlled by MrOwl and other companies owned by or under common ownership as MrOwl, which also includes our subsidiaries (i.e., any organization we own or control) or our ultimate holding company (i.e., any organization that owns or controls us) and any subsidiaries it owns. These companies will use your personal information in the same way as we can under this Privacy Policy;
    * Third-party vendors and other service providers that perform services on our behalf, as needed to carry out their work for us, which may include identifying and serving targeted advertisements, providing mailing services, providing tax and accounting services, web hosting, or providing analytics services; 
    * The public when you provide feedback on our Service. For example, if you post User Content on our blog or comment on our social media sites, your information, such as your first name, last initial, state of residence, and your comments, may be displayed on our Service or on our social media pages;
    * Other parties in connection with a company transaction, such as a merger, sale of company assets or shares, reorganization, financing, change of control or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company or third party, or in the event of a bankruptcy or related or similar proceedings; and 
    * Third parties as required by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) to enforce our Terms of Service or to protect the security or integrity of our Service; and/or (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of MrOwl, our visitors, or others.

We may also share information with others in an aggregated or otherwise anonymized form that does not reasonably identify you directly as an individual. 

**
  4. CONTROL OVER YOUR INFORMATION
**  

    * **Profile and data sharing settings.** You may update your profile information, such as your name and profile photo, and may change some of your data sharing preferences through the “Settings” page on the website or the mobile app.
    * **Access to your device information.** You may control the Service’s access to your device information through your “Settings” app on your device. For instance, you can withdraw permission for the Service to access your address book, location, files, photo stream, and camera. 
    * **How to control your communications preferences.** You can stop receiving promotional email communications from us by clicking on the “unsubscribe link” provided in such communications. We make every effort to promptly process all unsubscribe requests. You may not opt out of service-related communications (e.g., account verification, transactional communications, changes/updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices).
    * **Modifying or deleting your information.** If you have any questions about reviewing, modifying, or deleting your information, or if you want to remove your name or comments from our Service or publicly displayed content, you can contact us directly at [privacy@mrowl.com.](mailto:privacy@mrowl.com) We may not be able to modify or delete your information in all circumstances. 

**
  5. THIRD-PARTY TRACKING AND ONLINE ADVERTISING
**

We participate in interest-based advertising and use third party advertising companies to serve you targeted advertisements based on your online browsing history and your interests. We permit third party online advertising networks, social media companies and other third-party services, to collect, information about your use of our Sites over time so that they may play or display ads on our Sites, on other websites, apps or services you may use, and on other devices you may use. Typically, though not always, the information used for interest-based advertising is collected through cookies or similar tracking technologies. We may share a common account identifier (such as an email address or user ID) or hashed data with our third-party advertising partners to help identify you across devices. We and our third-party partners use this information to make the advertisements you see online more relevant to your interests, as well as to provide advertising-related services such as reporting, attribution, analytics and market research. 

To learn more about interest-based advertising and how you may be able to opt-out of some of this advertising, you may wish to visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s online resources, at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>, and/or the DAA’s resources at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. You may also be able to set your browser to delete or notify you of cookies by actively managing the settings on your browser or mobile device. Please note that some advertising opt-outs may not be effective unless your browser is set to accept cookies. Furthermore, if you use a different device, change browsers or delete the opt-out cookies, you may need to perform the opt-out task again. You may also be able to limit certain interest-based mobile advertising through the settings on your mobile device by selecting “limit ad tracking” (iOS) or “opt-out of interest-based ads” (Android).

_**Google Analytics and Advertising.**_ We use Google Analytics to recognize you and link the devices you use when you visit our site or Service on your browser or mobile device, log in to your account on our Service, or otherwise engage with us. We share a unique identifier, like a user ID or hashed email address, with Google to facilitate the service. Google Analytics allows us to better understand how our users interact with our Service and to tailor our advertisements and content to you. For information on how Google Analytics collects and processes data, as well as how you can control information sent to Google, review Google's site “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps” located at <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.You can learn about Google Analytics’ currently available opt-outs, including the Google Analytics Browser Ad-On here <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

We may also utilize certain forms of display advertising and other advanced features through Google Analytics, such as Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, the DoubleClick Campaign Manager Integration, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. These features enable us to use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick advertising cookie) or other third-party cookies together to inform, optimize, and display ads based on your past visits to the Service. You may control your advertising preferences or opt-out of certain Google advertising products by visiting the Google Ads Preferences Manager, currently available at <https://google.com/ads/preferences>, or by visiting NAI’s online resources at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>. 

**
  6. HOW WE STORE AND PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION
**

**Data storage and transfer** : Your information collected through our Service may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which MrOwl or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates, or service providers maintain facilities. If you are located in other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction. 

**Keeping your information safe:** : We care about the security of your information and employ physical, administrative, and technological safeguards designed to preserve the integrity and security of all information collected through our Service. However, no security system is impenetrable, and we cannot guarantee the security of our systems 100%. In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and, where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations.

**
  7. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY
**

MrOwl does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13 on this Service. In the event that we learn that we have inadvertently collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@mrowl.com](mailto:privacy@mrowl.com)

**
  8. LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES AND SERVICES
**

The Service may contain links to and from third-party websites of our business partners, advertisers, and social media sites and our users may post links to third-party websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies. We strongly recommend that you read their privacy policies and terms and conditions of use to understand how they collect, use, and share information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content on the websites of third-party sites. 

**
  9. HOW TO CONTACT US
**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the Service, please contact us at [privacy@mrowl.com](mailto:privacy@mrowl.com).

**
  10. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY
**

We may modify or update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect the changes in our business and practices, so you should review this page periodically. When we change the policy in a material manner, we will let you know and update the ‘last modified’ date at the bottom of this page. If you object to any changes, you may close your account. Continuing to use our Service after we publish changes to this Privacy Policy means that you are consenting to the changes.

This privacy policy was last modified on February 1, 2019.
